[Music]
Hey Indu, how are you? Hello Be I'm
good. How are you? Yes, very very good.
Thank you. Um I've you know like when
you look at the entire um tools in
action uh different sessions um yours
was one I was particularly interested in
because um yeah uh I I guess working
when things are in real time is
definitely adding a difficulty to
already a bit of a difficult space. So
um yeah uh keen to to to hear about it.
So I I'll let you share uh all your
knowledge. Thank you. Thank
you. Hello everyone. Uh this is Indu and
I work for Cisco systems. I'm a senior
software engineer and
architect. So today whatever I'm going
to discuss I'm discuss I'm going to
discuss more about how we can
dynamically configure the user interface
along with the backend backend
infrastructure and how AI can
collaborate along with the platform to
do uh these things dynamically.
So and today's session I'm not going to
going to walk through code session but
yes the futuristic concept concept I'm
going to talk about so just look how how
interface is getting changed into the
into the modern era right now users
expectation is totally changed
drastically changed I can see they want
a proactive interactive dynamic
productive and personalized interface
along Along with the accountability
traditional interface you know it is
reactive and it is more of a you user
predefined feature right fixed and
restricted feature that user could have
along with the interface but as we know
like a low code got very famous and user
can create uh create interface in real
time and personalize their interface
according to their need. Now how AI is
going to transform these particular
things? AI is going to involve into the
infrastructure or or we can say platform
infrastructure and connect in real time
so that whatever whatever code developer
earlier used to write to to to leverage
the low code infrastructure now AI
taking place and AI controlling how or
what format user want to see the data
and to the interface and uh other part
is that how how AI is going to control
data. So yes, it is a lot of lot of
discussion behind the scene happening
how how public uh public generated
models can connect with the connect with
the uh user data. Nobody wants to let
that connect right. So my explore is
that how we can create a close binding
between between the genai plus our user
specific data in a authentication and
etherization way so that they can
connect in real time they can merge with
each other and then produce produce a
result as user
want right so what GI enables geni
enables predictive rendering context
aware adjustments and self optimization
and all these can connect together and
create a beautified user experience to
the to the user right
so predictive rendering rendering means
that AI anticipate like user action and
pre prepare a UI element in advance
context awarement is similar like AI
personalized user interface based on
user behavior and user preferencees That
is what I was talking that is really
important into the new era of software
and self optimization. AI learn from
interaction to improve the prospective
of the user and actually let user notify
what user want to do with the platform
or how platform can be more useful to
the
user and how it can be done. So earlier
I was saying like uh uh LLM based genai
client right what they do they they are
public uh uh open public uh prompt right
and it's go directly to the directly to
the LM server and connect and response
what is uh how I can see the future is
it can connect with the connect with the
user data and how it can connect if we
have something in middleware so that
that
that request go to the middleware where
application data and API is sitting and
they make connection with the LLM models
right and then then client goes to the
server I mean when I say server it is
local server and connect with the
connect with the data uh databases
connect with the connect with the files
connect with
the connect with the resources that user
has and Then in the response data coming
from the user user uh resources and then
formation of data and learning over data
and and beautifying and uh uh
personalizing that data it is going to
be happen through the genai. So you know
if I give the data and tell geni hey I
need a table or I need a pie chart that
is get compiled inside the inside the
application client and then it is going
to going to deliver to the to the user
according to the preferences that user
user asking about data maybe after after
getting used to the platform user asking
like a statical data or contextual data
that user don't know how how user can
see the data better. So user can again
prompt through the platform hey I need
this particular data but I want to be
specific format where I can see the
analysis onto the data and where I can
make the decision. So what it what is
happen behind the scene? We request a
client and client goes connect with the
data get the data and then client
connect with the LLM models also and try
to communicate that hey this is the data
and format according to the user need
right so what it does it compile behind
the scene and it it return whole
formatted data into the interface now
user responsibility to save those data
or arrange according to their need and
and enable interface right there so that
user can come and explore that data
again and again according to their
preferences and choices. So whatever low
code used to do or no code platform used
to do everything that that whole
responsibility could be taken from the
genai and data is there user understand
where is the data and how to communicate
with the data and compile together and
get the get the response the way user
want and uh here is the breakthrough
like uh
uh we talk a part about model context
protocol that is that is uh pretty much
exciting protocol right now in AI
industry right what it does it is
connect connect the dot between genai
versus user data so here uh in the in
the big picture in the high level like
how user connect user connect for data
into the server and user wants the data
the way they want to see that data so
the the user request for the data and
it's go to the MCP client MCP client
connect to the server MCP server and get
the data and behind the scene what is
happen is genai involve into that one
and connecting with that data and
returning the data that user wants in
their way right so this is this is kind
of breakthrough uh like
like happening happening in AI industry
uh a lot of companies developing like a
you can hear all agentic uh agentic
programming right what is happen we have
a context I mean we have a file and
folder and then jai connect those file
and folder modify according to the user
need I mean creating a getting getting
reference of the functions from the from
the ji server and at the same time what
it does it is connect with the connect
with the local data and create a create
a source code similarly
Just think about it. If we have a
platform and platform has a prompt to
connect with the MCP client and the good
part is MCP client is kind of it we can
build inside MSP client whole AAA
feature like authentication
authorization and
accountancy so that user can connect
with the data safely at the same time it
connect with the genai with a trusted
source and return the data
more more accountable way. So so that no
uh if we are enabling such kind of
technology in the platform it can be
more secure and protected at the same
time it has all the feature capabilities
that geni already have uh like GPT let's
suppose someone using GPD uh model right
it has everything whatever chat GPD can
give or or
GPT LM can give at the same time it it
is connecting with the connecting with
the extra external data source. External
means user data source, right? And
combine them together and returning the
user returning the response according to
the user need. That is what the what the
what the uh what I was trying to explain
and how how the platform is platform
specific software is going to look
like and here conclusion of my task is
real time optimization. uh we know like
uh like geni is very powerful and it can
do a lot of things but if we leverage
this genai into the platform itself and
let them connect with the data in real
time then we are not worry about how we
can for we can format the data it is it
is happening behind the scene at the
same time in real time so we do not have
to develop lot of lot of endpoints
according to user need. We are kind of
optimizing whole development process and
letting letting geni control the data
and data formation. Maybe the data is
going to use for table or chart or or
some another purposes or maybe analysis
or maybe counters or maybe textual data
formations right or maybe message based
on those data that is going to be happen
in real time. So lot of optimization
happening behind the scene by leveraging
such such scenario into the into the
platform and AI powered adaptability
like as I say uh it is it is very very
dynamic like and we can kind of
um we can we can leverage this
technology by without without manual
intervention. it is happening in real
time and let's suppose it is response
data in different format we can again
communicate a prompt to the prompt to to
the MCP client uh to to redefine the
data it will be redefined from the
background and return if user is not
agree again can can keep going uh in the
loop and till satisfied it can interact
with that and get the response as they
need Right. Uh proactive performance uh
uh tuning as I said like the more you
are connecting connecting with the data
through MCP client uh from the platform
it is it is learning again and again how
you are used to interact sometime let's
suppose your your uh your prompt is
prompt message is not appropriate but
but the geni understand what really you
are looking and it's connect with the uh
contextual ual resource that user have
and and format the data accordingly. So
it can sense what user are really really
looking for that and uh by doing that I
said like it is going to
uh improve the uh user experience at the
same time it is going to uh like
leverage it scalability and efficiency
without without u
without human intervention in everything
is happening in real time and future
ready approach is MCP uh integrated
Next gen AI for continuous improvement
that is going to happen and you can see
when I say MCP it is not a single agent
agent protocol it is one to one and we
can build as many as MCP client and
server together so that so that we can
we can have information specific data as
user needed like one one one MCP client
and server for the for the for the
textbased data data, one for the for the
database oriented, one for the uh time
series data like we can build in future
as many as we want according to the
context needs so that it cannot
collide with each other and it should be
very very specific what user want and
how user
want with this. Thank you so much. And I
know it was a very very uh crisp and uh
15 minutes talk. So I I tried myself to
to to have the information as limited as
I can. But yes, if you want to connect
with me and and uh want further
information, I'll be available with you.
Thank you so much, Indu. like I really
enjoyed this and as you said it's
definitely a lot of knowledge uh packed
into a very short period of time. Uh but
this is what we like you know so um so
thank you for that. Um a very quick side
thank you as well that you're the only
speaker that respected the time for the
Q&A. So kudos for you on this. Um we
actually have a couple of questions and
actually a quick note before like um
really good point and spot some point
about the MCP like obviously there's a
lot of like different standards as well
arising. I don't know if you saw but
like um Microsoft officially is going to
support also like uh Google's A2A. So
that's going to be also an interesting
one to see how it develops. Um now
jumping into what the community wants to
ask you. So I think I'll just pick one
or two because again we have only three
minutes. So a question on um from Shrea.
How can developers ensure performance
and scalability with dynamic interfaces?
I'm just going to maybe add something to
it because this is very broad but like
maybe what are some lowhanging fruits uh
for devs. Yeah, that is a very nice
question like uh earlier in my talk I
told I said the keyword like low code,
right? And what low code is do is let
user to communicate with the data and
then let user to write a query and
format that data accordingly. Right? So
just think about it if as a as a user
I'm writing those query onto the
platform it can be not that performant
as jai can generate nowadays right. So
if we we can give or pass through the
right structure to the genai and saying
in real time write a query to merge the
data in the efficient or uh fastest way
it can build and it can also suggest how
how it can tweak to the structure if
user want to leverage that structure
behind the scene right
so that is I'm just trying to say
whatever low code or no code was doing
eliminate that and other than
that inbuilt the genai along with the
data and let them do what they were what
what what what user wants to do and
having control MCP has a control layer
so that you are not exposing data
directly to the genai it is you are you
are you are limited exposing your data
and you are having control on top of it
also
that makes sense thank you so much for
Uh such a crisp answer. Um well, I think
we are running perfectly on time. So
just wanted to say again a huge thank
you. I don't know if you had the chance
to look on the community chat, but uh a
lot of uh devs here have really enjoyed
the talk. So thank you so much, Indu.
Yeah, thank you. Thank you.